Front End Developer I MAXWELL RENATA JAMES YOUNG

Phone: 02041349603 | Email: maxtheyoung@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/maxwellyoung

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxwell-young-a55032125/

Introduction:

I'm excited about my recent pivot to software development. I've been doing music full-time but I've always been passionate about technology and it's very rewarding finally embarking on full stack development. I will continue pursuing music as a passion rather than a job.

Personal Attributes:

Excellent communicator – active listener, who asks questions to clarify expectations Critical thinker and problem solver - excited by the prospect of solving issues in an efficient manner

Excellent interpersonal skills – supportive team player but equally comfortable working alone, taking ownership

Self-management – punctual, reliable, hard-working, persistent, honest.

Professional Summary:

Web development / Programming - HTML, CSS/SASS/Tailwind, Javascript, React/Redux, Git, Express, Python, SQL, Figma, Node.js, REST APIs, Agile methodologies, Group work Social media – International audience management and profile development

Game development - Unity SDK, Gamemaker Studio

Music composition – Ableton Live, Logic Pro X, Pro Tools, Product & social channels; Casey Neistat, Yu Mei, The Forest Cantina, Gary Vee

Proficient in MS Office suite, Google docs

Photography / Videography - Experienced with cameras, software and shoot environments filling different roles

Experience:

April 2022 - July 2022 Dev Academy Aotearoa

Student / Apprentice - Software Development Bootcamp

An intensive 15-week programme in web development designed to provide you with the skills and knowledge needed to become a full stack developer. Technologies taught included HTML, JS, CSS, React JS, Redux, SQL, Git, databases, test driven development as well as the freedom to endeavour with new technologies. There was a large focus on human skills which covered bias, difficult conversations, conflict manage, diversity, Agile methodologies etc. We worked on projects in groups using pair programming and Agile roles to simulate a real world work environment.

https://maplearn.herokuapp.com/

For my teams final project, our goal was to create an interactive map that gave you some basic information about each clicked country. From there we discussed what we could add to this clickable map and were quickly interested in creating a game mode, fitting for an

educational website. I was our product manager and really enjoyed ensuring the user experience was always on top of our minds when making additions or changes to our project. I worked on the projects planning, game logic and layout. If I had more time, I would have improved it by fixing our styling and lack of responsiveness which I intend to amend for my portfolio in the near future.

2016 - present - Self employed recording artist

I produce and write my own music with fellow New Zealander Eddie "Lontalius" Johnston. I've become fluent producing using the software Ableton and have grown comfortable collaborating with others in a studio environment. Being an independent artist has required me to self manage myself with deadlines, promotion, etc.

- Composed recorded and produced music projects to multiple music platforms generating income from more than forty million plays.
- Performed on tour with Red Bull NZ,
- Planned and implemented performances in Auckland and Wellington
- 2020: Signed on for cancelled (due to Covid-19) Clairo Australia Tour
- 2019 Snail Mail Support Tour, Red Bull Music Tour
- 2017 Opened for Six60, Corporate event with Tuatara
- 2016 Performed onstage with multi-Grammy Award winning artists The Internet and Peanut Butter Wolf as well as several NZ artists (Maala, NameUL and Drax Project etc)

May 2021 - Feb 2022 Yu Mei

Dispatcher - Casual/Temporary 9-5

Fulfilling orders which involved organising order forms, collecting dispatch ready work and completing final packaging ready for courier collection, and generally doing anything that needed doing. Reported to the Production Manager Brigette Thomas.

September 2021 – Dec 2021 Floridita's and Loretta restaurants

Kitchen Porter - Dishwasher

Managed/responsible for stocking plate and glassware, ensured the kitchen ran smoothly behind the scenes to enable the rest of the team to complete their roles with more ease

Education & Qualifications:

2022 - Dev Academy Aotearoa - Certificate - Level 6 Web Development Training Scheme

2021 - Completed Harvard University's CS50: Introduction to Computer Science through FDX

2018 – Bachelor Commercial Music – Massey University, Wellington (incomplete)

2018 - Certificate - Intro to Espresso - Mojo Coffee

2017 - NCEA level 3 - English, Classical Studies, Music, Media Studies, Art Design

Other Achievements:

Volunteer Beach Clean Up Work

2017 – Awarded Wellington College Most Promising Musician Trophy

2016 - Senior Composer Award

2015 – Junior Composer Award

2015-2017 Wellington College Choral

References:

References are available upon request